so back to our overall reducing the amat
we've seen some techniques to reduce the
hit time
we've seen techniques to reduce the miss
rate we've seen a technique for using
the miss penalty which is to overlap
multiple misses
and we will now see a technique called
multi-level caches or having a cache
hierarchy instead of just one cache
with this technique a miss in the first
cache that the processor accesses which
is called now a level one cache we'll
just go to another cache instead of
memory
so now
the miss penalty from our level one
cache is not equal to the memory latency
the miss penalty in level one cache now
is the hit time of the level two cache
plus when the level two cache misses
then it's gonna be level two miss rate
times the level two miss penalty
and this level two miss penalty can be
the actual memory latency but we can
have a level 3 cache and if we miss
their level 4 cache and so on